O sunar za no to rai za auga.
Whoa.
Everything looks way brighter now.
So this is night vision magic.
I guess spriggans are good
for something after all.
I don't know if that was
a compliment or a diss.
You're practicing the magic you can use.
That's the important thing.
And projecting illusions
is one of your specialties.
Illusions?
Yeah, to trick people with.
It's cool, but it's not gonna
help anyone much in combat.
But you never know in a
life-or-death situation
your lame spriggan magic
might actually come in handy.
Now that was a diss.
Of Me Make a mistake Allow we run it
The darkness I find
Don't make me out where I am
I will Look the future
If you're just a little bit,
you'll be able to do it.
If you're in the middle of the
sky, you'll be able to fly.
future, you'll be able to fly.
No, you're just memorizing the words.
You have to learn what the
words of power mean first,
then match them with the
effects of the magic.
That's how you memorize spells.
I never thought I'd be in a game and have
to memorize words from
a different language.
Oh, and just so you know, the higher-ranked
spells have about 20 words. Holy crap.
I'll just stick to fighting then.
Would you quit complaining?
Oh, someone's messaging me.
Sorry, I have to get this. Sure.
It's Recon again.
It's probably nothing,
but I'll check anyway.
It says, I was right, be careful, S.
That's it.
What's that mean? S?
Sa-shi-su-oh.
What's wrong?
Oh, nothing.
Daddy, I'm picking up movement behind us.
Are they monsters?
Uh-uh. They're players. A lot.
Twelve total. You're kidding.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
We better take cover.
Okay, but where?
Just leave everything to me.
Hey, easy.
Sheik, Shalu, Obis, Grone, Loputo.
We can talk, but we have to
be really quiet about it.
Anything louder than a whisper,
and it's going to break the spell.
Okay.
They'll be coming into view soon.
What is that? You see it? Huh?
No, I can't see anything.
I can tell it's not a player.
It's got red eyes.
Kind of like a bat.
Why'd you break our cover?
Because that thing out there is
a high-level tracing searcher.
We have to destroy it.
Eku, skicho, tutuge, tumala, Start.
Come on, we gotta go.
Can't we just hide behind
one of your spells again?
They already know we're here.
That tracer had us pegged.
Hiding's not going to do us any good.
Besides, that bat was a
fire element familiar.
That can only mean the ones
who are tracking us are...
The salamanders.
What's a party of salamanders
doing way down here?
Whoa, check out the lake.
Looks like we're going to get away.
Watch where you're
going or you'll fall in.
That won't work.
Why didn't you tell me that before?
Oh, right, like it's my
fault you're in a hurry.
It's an earth magic barrier.
You can bash on it all day
and it won't destroy it.
Can we jump in the lake
and swim around it?
Nope.
At least, not unless you want to be lunch.
The water is filled with
high-level monsters.
The Undines are the only ones who
can take those kinds of things on.
Then I guess the only
option left is to fight.
I'm not going to argue with
that, but it won't be easy.
If the Salamanders have high-level
earth magic, it can only mean one thing.
They have a powerful mage on their side.
Leafa, I know you're good with the
sword, so don't take this the wrong way.
But could you back me up from here on in?
I need you to stay behind
and focus on healing me.
That way I can fight harder
and not worry about my HP.
They're targeting him
with everything they got!
Lisa Park!
Rando Doroto!
Lisa! Soap!
Su-fi-la-he-do-as-ta-lu-proto-supal-bani!
Uh-oh.
What do we do?
He's gonna run out of HP at some point.
That's enough, Kirito!
If we lose, it'll just mean a
couple extra hours of flying!
Let's give up while we can!
No way.
As long as I'm alive, I'm not
gonna let anyone in my party die.
I won't let that happen again.
What the hell? What's he doing?
Hurry!
This is your only chance!
What do you mean?
You have to use all the Main you have!
Hurry and focus on shielding
him from the next magic attack!
Uh, okay.
But I don't think it's gonna help.
Deku, Baupa, Eugene,
Rando, Musti, Kara, Ressa!
Su, Shalu, Lindo, Ashnia, Batu, Emi, Ogu!
Mama, Sepa! Speldo!
Rando, Doroto!
Do it now, Daddy!
He's using illusion magic.
But all that's going to do is make
him look like a giant monster.
Is that...Kirito?
Idiots!
Don't break formation!
It's not real!
Don't be afraid!
He can't hurt us if you stick to
the plan and stay in formation!
Hit him with an explosion spell!
Ayahu! Fala!
Fala! Hey Han!
Ah!
Retreat! Retreat!
RETREAT!
Stop it!
Wait, Kirito!
Hold on, don't kill him!
Isn't my daddy amazing?
Oh, my...
Okay, if you want to live, you better
tell me who sent you asshats after us.
Never.
Kill me if you want.
You got it.
Oh, man.
Now that was cool.
That was an awesome fight. Huh?
Your plan wasn't shabby either.
If I was alone, I wouldn't have
lasted a minute against you dorks.
What are you telling him that for?
Let me handle this. Listen up.
I want to see if you
and me can make a deal.
Check it out.
Those are all the items in Yul'd
I want after beating your asses.
All you have to do is answer my
questions and they could be yours.
Sound good?
Seriously?
Totally.
Ugh, men.
It's like they forgot we're even here.
Earlier this evening, I got
an urgent text from Jitakasu.
He's the leader of the mage
squad, or, well, he used to be.
Anyway, I got this text telling
us all to meet him here.
And when I showed up, he said he needed
12 of us to go on a hunt for two players.
At first, I thought it was overkill, but,
well, he said you guys took
out Kagemune, so it made sense.
Who's this Kagemune guy?
He's the leader of the Lancer Squad,
and he's known for hunting sylphs.
But yesterday, he got creamed
in a fight and had to retreat.
That was you guys, wasn't it?
Wait, why is Jitakasu so interested
in getting us out of the way?
Well, the order came from the top.
Something about you interfering
with the plan. Yeah? What plan?
Hey, hey, I'm just a grunt.
They don't tell me anything.
But I'm pretty sure something
really big's about to go down.
When I logged on today,
I saw this big-ass swarm of salamander
troops heading up north. No way.
They're going to go try to clear
the world tree, aren't they?
I doubt that.
Someone figured that to take the tree,
the whole army would need
ancient weapon-class equipment,
and we can't afford that stuff.
That's everything I know, I promise.
You weren't lying about your
end of the deal, were you?
No.
I'm a man of my word, partner.
Hey,
that big, ugly monster that was tearing
everything up, was that you or an illusion?
Yeah, I don't remember.
Wait, you don't know?
Not really, it just happens sometimes.
In the heat of battle, I'll snap
and can't remember a thing after.
Whoa, scary.
I think I remember most of what
happened this last time, though.
Like, I know I used that spell
Yui suggested. Do it now!
I also remember getting huge.
That was cool.
I remember losing my sword
and then grabbing people.
And you were chomping down
on them, remember that?
Oh, yeah.
I totally felt like a monster,
all eating people and everything.
So, uh, what did they taste like?
Kind of like grilled meat
just before it gets burnt.
All crispy and...
Okay, good. Sorry I asked.
Ow!
Wow, so this is LeGru.
Ow, that hurt.
Then you shouldn't be biting people.
I'll say.
Why is everyone ganging up on me?
I was trying to break the tension
with a stupid joke is all.
Bite me again and I'll cut you in half.
Yes, ma 'am.
Oh, look!
Hey, I just remembered something.
Right before those salamanders attacked
us, you got a message from your friend.
Oh, I totally forgot.
Rekon's not online.
Maybe he's asleep.
Okay, well, why don't you
log out and give him a call?
Yeah, I think I better check in with him.
I'll only be gone a sec.
Wait for me here, okay?
Yui, would you please keep
an eye on my avatar? Me?
Yeah, I need to make sure your dad
doesn't mess around with it while I'm out.
Copy that, ma 'am.
You gotta be kidding.
Hey, Nagata.
What's with all the calls?
What do you want? You picked up! Finally!
Where were you, Suguha?
I was dealing with some in-game stuff.
We got trouble!
Like, big trouble!
Sigurd's coming after
us, and that's not all!
He betrayed Sakuya, the self commander!
Betrayed her? How?
Start from the beginning and
tell me everything that happened.
But we're running out of time!
Okay, remember when the salamanders
ambushed us in the ancient forest?
Didn't that whole setup seem a little...
weird to you?
I don't know, not really.
Why do you think it was weird?
Remember how Sigurd said he'd be the decoy
and then he lured three of them away?
Yeah, now that you mention it...
Don't you think it was out of character?
I mean, usually he'd make
someone else do it, right?
Yeah, I guess.
I mean, you're right, it's
weird, but what's your point?
Okay, here it is.
I found out he's been working
as a spy for the Salamanders,
probably for a while now.
What?
Do you have proof or did
you just hear about it?
Remember how I said
something was bugging me?
Well, I used a transparency spell and
I've been following Sigurd all day.
I tracked him to a back
alley and I saw him
and a couple others put
on invisibility cloaks.
They were up to something,
that's for sure.
I followed them down into the sewers where
these two sketchy guys
were waiting for them.
I couldn't believe it.
They were salamanders.
They were a little ways away from
me, so I couldn't hear everything.
But I heard the salamanders
say they put a tracer on you.
Keep going then, what the
salamanders caught me?
I'm still in the sewers,
paralyzed by the poison arrow.
Well now, I know why
you kept calling me irl.
There's something else, Sakuya is
supposed to form an alliance with the cat.
See today, the meeting's
in neutral territory,
and she's heading there
right now in secret.
Sigurd knows about it too.
He's gonna show up at
the signing ceremony.
with his guns and attack it!
We have to hurry!
Hey, welcome back, Leafa.
Yeah, welcome back!
Kirito, I have to leave. Why?
Sorry, but there's something I
have to take care of right away.
If I had time to explain,
believe me, I would.
But I can't, and I don't think
I'll be coming back here either.
Then I guess you'll just have
to explain it to me on the way.
It'll take a while to get out
of here because we can't fly.
That's enough time, right?
Yeah, right.
Forty minutes from now, in
the Valley of the Butterflies,
the leaders of the Sylphs and the
Cat Sea are going to have a meeting.
Mind if I ask a couple
questions before we get there?
Go ahead.
If the Salamanders attack
the Sylphs and the Cat Seas,
what are they going to get out of it?
For one, they'd stop the
Alliance from happening.
And if the Catsy find out their leader
died because a Sylph turned traitor?
they'd be pretty pissed, wouldn't they?
Super pissed.
It's a good way to start a war between
the Catsy and the Sylphs, that's for sure.
It's also a good way to get rich.
If you take out the leader of a
territory, you get 30 % of its money.
You can invade its hometown for 10
days and charge whatever tax you want.
No way, really?
Seriously, would I lie to you?
This isn't your problem, Kirito.
It's a sylph problem.
You don't have any reason to get
involved and risk your life over it.
If we go to the meeting, chances
are we won't make it back alive.
And we'll probably have to
start over from Sylvain again.
But this could work for you.
You want to get to the top
of the world tree, so...
You might be better off
working with the salamanders.
if they can pull this off it'll
give them the power and resources
they need to make an attempt at
the world tree and since you're a
spriggan they might hire you as a
mercenary so if you wanted to kill
me you could i wouldn't hold it
against you it's just a game in the end
anything goes right if you want to kill
you kill if you want to steal you steal
a lot of people think like that more
than I care to know and in a way I
get it even I used to think like that
but none of it's true in a virtual
world there's things you have to protect
because it's a virtual world someone
special taught me that if you give in
to your impulses in here it's going
to change who you are in the real world.
The player and the character
are one and the same.
Leafa, you're a good person,
and I want to be your friend.
So it doesn't matter what the
reason is.
There's no way in hell I'd ever
attack a friend for my own benefit.
I couldn't live with myself.
Kirito, I...
Thank you.
Wow, I sounded pretentious, didn't I?
Sorry about that. Uh-oh.
That was pretty cool.
Oh, crap.
We're wasting time just standing here.
We gotta go. Yui, lead the way.
You got it, Daddy.
Here, give me your hand.
Okay, but... Come on!
The monsters!
Here's the exit!
I will be the same way.
I
have
no
feelings.
Next time, General of the Blazing Flame.